速 度 与 激 情  1
卡车上装满了值钱的货  正朝你的方向开去
Just packed up a real money load, and it's comin' your way.
在卡车侧面  写着"罗杰"的就是目标物
Look for "Rodgers" on the side of the truck.
别忘了我那一份
Don't forget my share of the deal.
该死!
Shit!
"杜洛托咖啡屋"
去边的鲔鱼三明治  对不对?
- Tuna on white, no crust, right?
我还没决定  今天的好吃吗?  在过去的三个礼拜中
- I don't know. How is it? - Every day for the last three weeks you've been comin' in here...
你天天问我鲔鱼三明治好不好吃
and you've been askin' me how the tuna is.
昨天很糟糕
It was crappy yesterday...
前天也不怎么样
it was crappy the day before
今天还是一样
- and guess what，It hasn't changed.
那就来份鲔鱼三明治吧  要去边吗?  是的
- I'll have the tuna. - No crust? - No crust.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这部车是有点不对劲  杰西  你看是什么毛病
Talk to me, Jesse. This ain't workin', brother.
应该是燃料系统漏油的问题
It's your fuel map. It's got a nasty hole.
所以在第三档就上不去  我就说是第三档吧
- It's why you're unloading in third. - I told you it was third.
我把脉冲喷油嘴加长一毫秒
I lengthen the injector pulse another millisec...
再调整氧化亚氮燃油注入器  问题就解决了
and just tune the NOS timer, you'll run nines.
这个傻瓜怎么回事  吃三明治好像吃上瘾了
What's up with this fool? What is he, sandwich crazy?
他才不是为吃而来
No, V. He ain't here for the food.
少胡扯  他是哈瑞新雇的销售员
Chill out, bro. He's just slingin' parts for Harry.
我知道他想干什么  他想和蜜雅上床
- I know what he's slingin'. - He's tryin' to get in Mia's pants.
你们怎么样?  蜜雅  你好吗?
- What's up, guys? - How you doin', Mia?
你还是活的那么刺激吗?
How you livin', girl?
唐  要饮料吗?
Hey, Dom. You want somethin' to drink?
他挺帅的嘛
Ah, he's beautiful.
我喜欢他的发型
I like his haircut.
文斯
Vince.
文斯!
Vince!
干什么?  你要吃什么?
- What? - Can I get you anything?
你今天很漂亮
You look good.
谢谢你  蜜雅  明天见
Thanks a lot, Mia. See you tomorrow.
好的
Sure.
明天?  我最喜欢这一段  不行
- Tomorrow? - Oh, I love this part.  -No
从现在起你改吃汉堡
Try Fatburger from now on.
只要两块九毛五就能吃一客  双层起司汉堡和薯条  死玻璃
You can get yourself a double-cheese with fries for 2.95, faggot.
我喜欢这里的鲔鱼三明治  胡说  没有人喜欢
- I like the tuna here. - Bullshit. No one likes the tuna.
我就喜欢
Well, I do.
天呐!  唐  你过来一下好吗?
Jesus Christ, Dom! Would you get out there?
烦死人了  告诉你我可不是开玩笑的
I'm sick of this shit! I'm not kidding, Dom!
快去呀!
Get out there!
你在三明治里放了什么东西  你以为自己很幽默
- What'd you put in that sandwich? - That's really funny.
唐!
Dom!
好啦
All right.
他在我面前张牙舞爪  现在是我在你面前
- He was in my face. - I'm in your face.
行啦  少逞强  你太让我没面子了
Relax! Don't push it! You embarrass me!
到那边去
Get over there!
杰西  把他的皮夹给我
Jesse, give me the wallet.
"布莱恩厄尔史皮尼"  像个杀人犯的名字
"Brian Earl Spilner." Sounds like a serial killer name.
你是杀人犯吗?  不是
- Is that what you are? - No, man.
以后不准再来这里
Don't come around here again.
我有行动的自由
Hey, man, you know this is bullshit.
你是替哈瑞做事吗?  对  才刚开始上班
- You work for Harry, right? - Yeah, I just started.
你已经被开除了
You were just fired.
"赛车边缘  高性能汽车零件"
唐老大  谢谢你大批的向我买货
Hey, Dominic, I appreciate what you did in a big way.
我永远记得你的恩惠
Dominic, I owe you.
布莱恩  你想让我关门吗
Brian, you're messin' with my business.
只要唐老大开车  他就是财神
When Dominic drives, he's golden.
大家都跑来买他所用的零件
Kids pour in here, want everything he has, every performance part...
而且都是付现金的
and they pay cash!
唐说了些什么?  你不会爱听的
- What did Dominic say? - You don't wanna know.
他到底说了什么?  他要你滚蛋
- What did Dominic say? - He wants you outta here.
他要我滚蛋?  没错
- He wants me outta here? - Yes!
那你又怎么说呢?  你想我能说什么?
- And what did you say to Dom? - What do you think I said?
我只能说"好帮手很难请"
I told him, "Good help is hard to find."
你放心
Relax.
我需要氧化亚氮燃油注入系统
I need NOS.
我要氧化亚氮燃油注入系统  不行
- I need NOS. - No.
今早我开到  时速140哩时就上不去了
My car topped out at 140 miles per hour this morning.
业余的人不用氧化亚氮
Amateurs don't use nitrous oxide.
我见过你开车  你的脚不够灵活
I've seen the way you drive. You got a heavy foot.
如果不改  迟早会出事  给我一个这种装置
- You'll blow yourself to pieces. - I need one of these.
要大的那种
One of the big ones.
等一下  给我两个吧
Actually, no. Let's make it two.
还有今晚我就要
And, Harry, I need it by tonight.
嘿  等一下  居然有个白小子出现
Hey, hold up, hold up. Look at this snowman right here, man.
喂  你的车都有什么装备
Sweet ride. What you runnin' under there, man?
想让我自己去发掘吗?  当然啦
- Making me find out the hard way? - Hell, yeah.
真勇敢  我叫海克特
You brave. You brave. They call me Hector.
我也有姓  但太难念  所以…
I got a last name too, but I can't pronounce it, so...
我是布莱恩
Brian Spilner.
典型的白人名字  你懂我的意思吧
Typical white boy name. Know what I'm sayin'?
你看到那边那辆车吗?
See that over there?
那是我的  不过今晚我不参加赛车
That's mine. It's my baby. But I ain't cuttin' her loose tonight.
为什么?  因为我想参加正统赛车
- Why not? - 'Cause I'm goin' legit.
我想参加劲爆拖车赛  你听过吗?
tryin' to get on the NI RA circuit. You heard about that?
当然听过
Hell, yeah.
你想干什么?  我在等杜洛托
- So what's up with you, man? - I'm just waitin' for Toretto.
大家都在等他
Shit. Better get in line.
这是你的车?  是呀  我不正站在它旁边吗
- This yours? - Yeah. I'm standin' next to it.
妙得很  有几件事或许你还不知道
That's funny. You know, Edwin happens to know a few things.
其中之一就是
And one of the things Edwin knows is...
你站不站在车旁不重要
it's not how you stand by your car.
重要的是你怎么赛车  老兄  最好搞清楚
It's how you race your car. You better learn that.
喔  他们来了  要开始罗
Oh, shit. Here they come. It's on.
唐  你好  嗨  卡美儿
- Dom, how you doin'? - Hey, Camille.
你在练瑜珈吗?
You been doin' yoga?
真的呀?  当然是真的  蒙妮卡!
You did? Of course you did. Monica.
我闻到一股狐骚味
I smell skanks.
再不走  小心我在你们脸上留点记号
Why don't you pack it up before I leave tread marks on your face?
莱蒂  我们只是聊聊天  是哟!
- Letty, I was just talkin'. - Whatever.
海克特
Okay, Hector.
老大  有什么事?
Yeah? What's up, man?
怎么样?  艾德温
- What's up? - Edwin.
今晚怎么比?  只赛一场
- How we doin' this tonight? - One race.
赌注两千美金  赢的人全拿
Two-G buy-in. Winner takes all.
海克特  你来管钱  为什么由海克特管钱?
- Hector, you're gonna hold the cash. - Why Hector?
他的车最慢  就算偷钱也跑不远
He's too slow to make away with the money.
祝你们好运  等等
- Good luck, guys. - Wait. Hold up.
我虽然没现金  但是我有车主证
I don't have any cash, but I do have the pink slip to my car.
你以为会拳击  就是拳王阿里的对手吗
You just can't climb in the ring with Ali 'cause you think you box.
他知道我打得好
He knows I can box.
我有个提议
So check it out. It's like this.
谁赢我  我的车就是他的
I lose, the winner takes my car, clean and clear.
但若我赢了  不但拿钱  也希望能赢得你们的尊敬
But if I win, I take the cash, and I take the respect.
尊敬
Respect.
对某些人来说尊敬蛮重要的
To some people, that's more important.
那是你的车?
That your car?
这里有一个空气压缩器
I see a cool-air intake.
一个氧化亚氮雾化系统  和四缸涡轮增压引擎
It's got a NOS-fogger system and a T-four turbo, Dominic.
还有AIC控制器
I see an AIC controller.
直接接到氧化亚氮的喷气嘴
It has direct port nitrous injection.
还有一个独立的燃料控制系统
Yeah, and a stand-alone fuel management system.
恐怕要花上一万块美金
Not a bad way to spend $10,000.
你看到了吗?
You see that shit?
那么多的氧化亚氮  足够把他炸成碎片
He's got enough NOS in there to blow himself up, period.
你说我值不值?
What do you say? Am I won'thy?
现在还不知道  不过你可以参加比赛
We don't know yet. But you're in.
咱们走
Let's go.
到底发生了什么事?
What the hell's goin' on around here?
这条路不通  你另外找路吧
Street's closed, pizza boy. Find another way home.
混蛋的飙车族
Goddamn street racers.
注意  这里情况很紧张
Iog on 22, code three. Tension is high.
他们把街道封锁了
They've blocked the street.
艾德温
Edwin...
不管你赢或输  我都是你的
this is yours, whether you win or lose.
但是如果你赢了  她也是你的
But if you win, you get her too.
你一定会赢
You're gonna win.
我绝对会赢
I'm gonna win.
接到报告  巴拉肯杂货店发生命案
We had a reported homicide, 187, at Barakian liquor.
格兰岱尔发生命案  警察全部出动
I've got a 187 in Glendale. Cops are all over it.
我们可以开始了  我再重复一次  可以开始了
We're good to roll. I repeat, good to roll.
我们开始赛车吧  好
- Let's race! - Right.
出发!
Go!
太棒了!
Hell, yeah!
天呀  那家伙可真快
Damn, that guy's fast.
我们急起直追"加油呀!  "
Let's go! "Menage a"!
完了  蒙妮卡泡汤啦
No! Monica!
"警告!  危险!  "
安静点!
Shut up!
加油呀!
Let's go now, baby!
你要的全在这里  给你
- Here's what you want, right here. - There you go.
你在和一群小鬼头赛车嘛
You were racin' a bunch of skateboards.
把钱交给我妹妹
My sister holds the money.
你要数清楚
Count it.
你就是我的奖品
And you're my trophy.
蒙妮卡宝贝  怎么样呀?
Hey, Monica! What's up, baby?
你有毛病吗  又没有赢
What's your problem, nigga? You didn't win.
去你的!
Fuck you, then!
你觉得好玩吗?  老弟  麻烦大了
- Was that fun? - Got a problem there, huh, buddy?
你傻笑个什么劲  我几乎赢了你
- What are you smilin' about? - Dude, I almost had you.
你几乎赢我?
You almost had me?
你没赢过我  连车也不是你的了
You never had me. You never had your car.
你换档时乱来一通  哪有那样踩双重离合器的
Granny shifting, not double-clutchin' like you should.
好在氧化亚氮  没把空气压缩器给烧掉
You're lucky that hundred-shot of NOS didn't blow the welds on the intake.
居然敢说几乎赢我
Almost had me?
现在我和我的天才科学家  得把这部车拆开
Now me and the mad scientist gotta rip apart the block...
好把被你烧掉的活塞环给换掉
and replace the piston rings you fried.
你去问问  任何一位真正的赛车手
Ask any racer, any real racer.
不管你是赢一英寸或一哩
It don't matter if you win by an inch or a mile.
赢就是赢
Winning's winning.
请注意  接到报告  在哈松区有飙车族在赛车…
Available units, we have reported street racing along Hawthorne...
要命!  警察来了
Oh, shit! We got cops!
快走!
Go!
唐  上车  快走!
Dom, get in the car! Go!
杜洛托  站住不准走!
Toretto, stop right there!
上车!
Get in!
没想到居然是你来救我
You're the last person in the world I expected to show up.
我想若能得到你的赏识  或许你会让我保留这部车
I thought if I got in your good graces, you might let me keep my car.
你是得到我的赏识  可惜我还是要你的车
You are in my good graces, but you ain't keepin' your car.
你车开得不错  以前是开车的吗?
You drive like you've done this before. What are you, a wheel man?
不是
NO!
那是偷车贼罗
You boost cars?
不是  坐过牢吗?
- No. Never. - Ever done time?
只进去过夜而已  没什么大不了的
Couple of overnighters. No big deal.
你不是曾为了偷车  在感化院待过两年吗?
What about the two years in juvie for boostin' cars?
在图桑对不对?
Tucson, right?
没错  我叫杰西去查你的资料
Yeah, I had Jesse run a profile on you, Brian Earl Spilner.
如今你可以在网站上  找到任何资料
He'll find anything on the Web, anything about anybody.
你何必去骗人?
So why bullshit?
那你呢?
So what about you?
在隆波克坐了两年牢
Two years in Lompoc.
我宁愿死也不要回去
I'll die before I go back.
真倒霉  怎么了?
- Oh, great. - What?
今晚将是个漫长的一夜
It's gonna be a long-ass night, that's what.
跟我们走
Follow us.
"哲学家孔子"
我们不是已达成协议了吗
I thought we had an agreement.
你走你的路  我过我的桥
You stay away, I stay away.
大家都高兴
Everybody stays happy.
强尼  你要我怎么说呢  我们迷路了
We got lost, Johnny. What do you want me to tell you?
他是谁?  我新请的技工
- Who's "we"? - My new mechanic.
布莱恩  这位是强尼
Brian, meet Johnny Tran.
穿蛇皮裤的那位是蓝斯  是他的表弟
The guy in the snakeskin pants, that's his cousin, Lance.
什么时候能  和你那部本田2000赛车呢?
So when are you gonna give me a shot at that Honda 2000 of yours?
这是你的车  本来是我的  现在是他的了
- This your ride? - It was. It's his now.
不是  我还没有验收
No, it's not. I haven't taken delivery.
所以是无主的车罗
Then it's nobody's car.
有人下了不少功夫嘛
Somebody put in the wrench time.
蓝斯  你说呢?  看起来很不错
- What do you think, Lance? - It's an amazing machine.
的确不错
Yes, indeed.
我们走
Let's go.
下个月摩哈比沙漠见
I'll see you in the desert next month.
你一定会输得屁滚尿流
Be ready to have your ass handed to you.
就凭这辆摩托车吗?
You're gonna need more than that crotch rocket.
到时候你自然会知道
I got somethin' for you.
这又是怎么回事?
What the hell was that about?
说来话长  以后再告诉你  我们快走
Long story. I'll tell you later. Let's get outta here.
要爆炸了!
NOS!
到底是怎么回事?
So, what the hell was that all about?
那是个很长的故事
It's a long story.
反正有二十哩的路要走  你就慢慢说吧
We got a 20-mile hike. Humor me.
一个变质的交易
A business deal that went sour.
再加上我不应该和他妹妹上床
Plus, I made the mistake of sleepin' with his sister.
嘿  布莱恩
Yo, Spilner.
要喝啤酒吗?
You want a beer?
喔!  糟糕
Oh, shit.
我们全都落在后面  对不对?
We were all there, right? Falling behind.
载着那些氧化亚氮  对
- With all that nitrous. - Yeah.
唐  我们正想去找你
Yo, Dom. We were just about to go lookin' for you, brother.
你到哪里去了?  那里有一大堆的警察
- Where were you? - There were mass cops there.
他们像排练过的一样  从每个方向开进来
They came in from every direction. Their shit was orchestrated.
这是你的啤酒?  对
- This your beer? - Yeah, that's my beer.
我的大天才  带她到楼上去
Yo, Einstein. Take it upstairs.
穿着衣服怎么享受嘛
You can't detail a car with the cover on.
连这种小事也搞不定
Can't even get that right.
你没事吧?
You all right?
你看我像没事吗?
Am I all right?
我只不过问问罢了
It was just a question.
唐  你把那菜鸟带来这里干嘛
Yo, Dom! Why'd you bring the buster here?
因为那个菜鸟救了我
'Cause the buster kept me out of handcuffs!
他没有忙着逃跑
He didn't just run back to the fort!
是他带我回来的
The buster brought me back.
只要是可乐娜  啤酒随你喝
You can have any brew you want... as long as it's a Corona.
谢谢你  那瓶是文斯的  好好享受吧
- Thanks, man. - That's Vince's, so enjoy it.
你...
You...
老大  厕所在哪里?
Hey, bro, you got a bathroom?
楼上右边第一间
Yeah, upstairs. First door on the right.
他没资格来这里
He's got no call bein' up in here.
你对他一点也不了解  唐  他说的不错
- You don't know that fool for shit! - He's right, Dom.
文斯  别忘了当初我也不了解你呀
Vince, there was a time when I didn't know you.
拜托那时候我们才小学三年级
That was in the third grade!
那些女人是你找来的吗?
Yeah, so, what girls are here?
什么样的都有  要我的吗?  你最好闭上…
- You name it. You want mine? - You need to shut the f...
你什么都没有  你看起来有点累
- You don't have anything? - You look a bit tired.
最好到楼上去替我按摩
I think you should go upstairs and give me a massage.
可是这些客人怎么办
Look at all our guests.
那就到楼上去由你替我按摩
How about we go upstairs and you give me a massage?
疯女人
Crazy lady.
记住你还欠我一部十秒内  能跑四分之一哩的极速车
You know you owe me a ten-second car, right?
哎哟!
Ouch.
有他好看的
Oh, shit.
马桶座垫你有擦干净吗?
Did you wipe the seat?
好啦  你别惹事好吗
Oh, Jesus Christ! Would you cut the shit already?
别这样!
Come on!
走  替我拿点饮料
Come on. Let's go get me a drink.
别走嘛  我们正在渐渐进入情况
Come on, man. We were just about to get along.
你要哪种饮料  只要是冰的都行
- So, what do you want? - Anything, long as it's cold.
我哥哥喜欢你  通常他谁也不喜欢
My brother likes you. He usually doesn't like anybody.
对  他蛮难懂的
Yeah, he's a complicated guy.
是吗?那你呢?
Yeah? What about you?
我简单多了  你连撒谎都不会
- I'm simpler. - You're a shitty liar.
我认为那是恭维
Well, I'll take that as a compliment.
现在有个问题  什么问题?
- But there's a problem. - What's that?
你得好好去睡一觉
You need to get some sleep.
而且肯定需要洗澡
And you definitely, definitely need a shower.
走  我送你回家
Come on. I'll take you home.
把手伸出来  很好  现在把车门打开
Show me your hands. Very good. Now open the door.
把手放在头后  放在你头后
Put your hands on your head. Behind your head.
面向车子  向后倒退到车尾
Face the front of the vehicle, walk backwards towards the rear.
向右走两步  停在那里
Take two steps to your right. Stop right there.
我做了什么?
What'd I do?
闭嘴  警官  他没武器
Shut up. He's clean, Sarge.
慕斯  拜托你把手铐拿掉
Damn! Muse, will you take these things off?
要命  弄得那么紧  要玩就玩真的
- Shit. You put 'em on so tight. - I like realism.
玩真的  否则万一被人看到就糟了
- You like realism. - You never know who's watching.
真漂亮  比上次被充公的房子要好多了
Nice crib, Sergeant. It's a lot nicer than that last place you confiscated.
这是艾迪费雪在五零年代  替伊丽莎白泰勒盖的
Ain't it? Eddie Fisher built this house for Elizabeth Taylor in the '50s.
连好莱坞的警察都有明星架势
See? Even the cops are Hollywood in Hollywood.
才把他从  杜洛托极速车天堂带过来
Here he is, fresh from Toretto's hot rod heaven.
那可是部八万美金的车子
That was an $80,000 vehicle, officer.
等等  你告诉他了吗?  他早就知道了
- Wait. You tell him what happened? - He knows what happened.
最好把帐单交给强尼  你居然跟我耍嘴皮子
- Send the bill to Johnny Tran. - The kid's givin' me attitude?
这会影响到  警方和FBI之间的关系
That doesn't speak very well for police-FBI relations, Tanner.
我一走进来  他就…  好了
- I walk in, the guy's already givin'... - All right, all right.
我们慢慢谈  好吗?
We'll talk, okay? Let's talk about it.
慕斯  请你给我们四杯冰卡布其诺
Muse, why don't you make us four iced cappuccinos, please.
走吧  要普通的还是低咖啡因的
- Come on. - Regular or decaf, Sarge?
低咖啡因的吧
Decaf, I think.
两个月内有四件抢劫案  我们一点线索都没有
Four hijackings in two months, and we don't have anything.
单是DVD放映机  和数位照相机就值一、两百万
DVD players and digital cameras alone are won'th a million-two...
加起来总值超过六百万美金
which brings the grand total to six million plus.
我们的官方压力非常大
We're in the political crosshairs now, Brian.
所以才让你去卧底
That's why you're undercover.
告诉你一件事  若你能帮我们结案
You want that detective badge fast, kid. And you wanna know something?
升官这件事就包在FBI身上
The FBI can help, if you come through for us.
卡车司机是怎么说的?  他给我们同样的描述
- What does the truck driver say? - He gave us the same M.O.
一共三辆本田喜美  驾驶技术高超
Three Honda Civics, precision driving...
车身底盘有绿色霓虹灯
the same green neon glow from under the chassis.
根据化验室的报告  刹车痕全都一样
Lab says the skid marks came back the same:
是藤原正统ZX轮胎
Mashamoto ZX tires.
所以一定是那些极速车
So we know that it's somebody in the street racing world.
我们若不能尽快解决
We don't make this case soon...
卡车司机们  就会自己采取激烈的手段
the truckers will take matters into their own hands.
我告诉他们已经快结案了
I tell 'em we're close.
难道你要我变成说谎的人
You gonna make me a liar?
先看看我们已有的资料
Look, what do we know?
我们都知道这和杜洛托有关
We all know this world revolves around Toretto, right?
虽然不见得是他亲自下的手
I'm not sayin' that he's necessarily the one that's poppin' these trucks...
但我保证他绝对知道是谁干的
but I can guarantee the both of you that he knows who is.
我需要时间…  你需要时间?
- It's just a matter of time until... - You want time?
我们已经没有时间啦
Buy the magazine. We don't have time.
尽快给我一些可以用的资料
Just get me something I can use.
哈瑞有没有好好合作?
Is Harry cooperating?
有  否则就叫他为收购赃物  到牢里去蹲个三、五年
Yeah, like a guy who's gonna do time for receiving stolen property if he doesn't.
他对杜洛托有什么评语
What kind of vibe is he getting from Toretto?
他很怕他  可是不认为  杜洛托会在闲暇时去抢卡车
He's scared of him, but he doesn't think he's jackin' trucks in his spare time.
因为杜洛托很有自制力  等一等
- He's too controlled for that. - Wait.
不是我不相信哈瑞的观察力
Not that I want to contradict Harry's fine judge of character...
但当初杜洛托  是因为差点打死人才去坐牢的
but Toretto did hard time for nearly beating a guy to death.
他血液里充满了氧化亚氮  脑袋里则充满了汽油
He's got nitrous oxide in his blood and a gas tank for a brain.
他绝非善类
Do not turn your back on him.
泰勒  我还需要一部车
Hey, Tanner. I'm gonna need another car.
那零件和服务怎么办?
What about parts and service?
先拖延一下  我真不知道该怎么办?
- Hold off on that. - What should I do with this?
在搞什么呀
All right, what the hell is this?
那是什么玩意?
What do you got there?
你的车呀  我的车?
- This is your car. - My car?
我要的是  十秒能跑四分之一哩的车
I said a ten-second car, not a ten-minute car.
这家伙只能用推的  或用拖车拖过终点线
You could push this across the finish line, or tow it.
恐怕连拖都拖不过终点
Couldrt even tow that across the finish line.
这么没信心呀
No faith.
我对你有信心  对这堆垃圾可没有
I have faith in you, but this isn't a junkyard.
我们这里是汽车修理厂  把车盖打开
- This is a garage. - Pop the hood.
把车盖打开?  对  打开它
- Pop the hood? - Pop the hood.
哇!  2JZ引擎
TwoJZ engine.
这么厉害  我不是早就告诉你了吗?
- No shit. - And what did I tell you?
我收回刚刚说的话  依我看
- I retract my previous statement. - You know what?
如果投资一万五  若需要隔夜送到的日本零件时
This will decimate all after you put about 15 grand in it...
可能要花更多的钱  但保证能打败所有的跑车
or more, if we have to overnight parts from Japan.
叫哈瑞先记在我的帐上好了
We'll put it on my tab at Harry's.
好!
Yes!
我得让你再去参加赛车  好从你身上赚上一笔钱
I gotta get you racing again so I can make some money off your ass.
你就去参加在加州  摩哈比沙漠举行的极速大赛
There's a show in the desert called Race Wars, and that's where you'll do it.
以后你下班后就过来帮忙
Tell you what. When you're not workin' at Harry's, you're workin' here.
如果在这里  还找不到顺手工具的话
If you can't find the right tool in this garage, Mr. Arizona...
那你根本没资格拥有车子
you don't belong near a car.
You don't belong near a car.
你是他的人了
He owns you now.
告诉我你的想法
Tell me what you think about this.
换成可调整的哥尼牌避震器
Koni adjustables.
就能帮我减少两磅的重量
Gonna save us about two pounds.
而且还能增加车轮的防滑性能
And they're gonna give us better traction for the hole shot.
好
All right?
这是这部车的基本设计
This is your basic layout of the car...
而那就是整理好后的成品
and that's pretty much what it could look like when it's finished.
红绿相间
Red, green.
天呐  你该进麻省理工学院
Man, you should be goin' to MIT or somethin'.
想得美
Yeah, right.
我得了…他们叫什么来着?
No, I got that... Oh, what's it called?
就是注意力无法集中…  所谓的ADD
- That attention disorder... - ADD?
对  就是那玩意
Yes, that shit. Yeah.
其实我的代数很好
You know, I was good in algebra and, like, math...
也很喜欢数学
and shit.
可惜其他科目全都一塌糊涂
Everything else I failed.
最后惨遭退学
Dropped out of school. I don't know.
但是不知道为什么
It's just somethin' about engines...
只有引擎能够使我平静下来
that calms me down, you know?
我走了  别这样嘛
- I'm outta here. - Come on, dog.
文斯  来这边帮我们一下
Vince, get over here and give us a hand.
老大  你根本不缺帮手嘛
Looks like you got all the help you need, brother.
蜜雅!    来啦
- Mia! - All right already.
鸡肉都烤干了  我马上就来
- The chickers dry. - I'm comin' out already.
等一等
Hey, hold up.
因为你是所有人中
Because you were the first out of everybody here...
第一个拿烤鸡的  所以由你说祈祷文
to reach in to get the chicken, you say grace.
亲爱的神圣的…
Dear heavenly, uh...
圣灵
Spirit.
圣灵  谢谢你
Spirit. Thank you.
嗯  谢谢你供应给我们
Uh, thank you for providing us with a direct port...
氧化亚氮喷气嘴
nitrous, uh, injection...
还有进气冷却器  和滚珠轴承涡轮增压器
four core intercoolers and ball-bearing turbos...
还有  嗯  镀钛活门弹簧
and, um, titanium valve springs.
谢谢你  阿门
- Thank you. - Amen.
很不错  阿门
- Not bad. - Amen.
他根本是在向车神祈祷
He was prayin' to the car gods, man.
这些烤鸡真好吃  你要什么?
- These are the best. - What do you want?
练习呀  谢谢你  宝贝
- Practice. - Thank you, girl.
看是谁回来了
Look who it is.
咱们的老朋友
Old Coyotes 'R' Us.
我还以为你不饿呢
I thought you werert hungry, pumpkin.
总得吃东西嘛  他永远吃不饱
- You know, I gotta eat. - He's always hungry.
好  快坐下来
All right, sit down.
蜜雅  你好吗?
How you doin', Mia?
杰西  把烤鸡给我  让咱们吃个够
- Jesse, hand me that chicken. - Let's eat some grub.
还要不要再来点烤鸡?  有没有租录影带?
- Want some of that chicken? - Did you rent a movie or somethin'?
你需要帮忙吗?
Need a hand?
不用了  你去和他们一起看录影带吧
No, I'm good. You can go join the boys watchin' the movie.
在我家是不让厨子善后的
Well, the cook doesn't clean where I come from.
那我真希望能去那里
I'd like to go there.
其实我们应该出去走走
I think we should go out sometime.
我不和我哥哥的朋友约会
No, I don't date my brother's friends.
不会吧
That sucks.
看来我得踢他几脚  那我倒想看
- I guess I'll have to kick his ass then. - I'd love to see that one.
就算要付钱我也心甘情愿
No, I would... I would pay to see that one, actually.
你忙完后就去替我洗车
Wash my car when you get done.
你是什么意思?  蜜雅  我不是说你
- What was that? - No, Mia.
我是指那个讨厌鬼
I'm talkin' to the punk.
还有把你最好的洋装穿上
And wear your favorite dress, 'cause when you're done...
因为等洗完车后你就该去接客了
I'm puttin' you on the street where you belong, cutie.
这个微波炉坏了吗?
Is this thing broken?
到底是怎么搞的
What's wrong with this thing?
文斯  你要带我去的  那家古巴餐厅叫什么名字?
V, what was that Cuban restaurant you wanted to take me to?
就是那间很有特色的餐厅
The one with the peccadillo and the...
有木头桌子上面放着红蜡烛  对  还有芭蕉树
- Red candles and the wooden table? - Yeah, the plantain too.
那家叫什么名字?  叫恰恰恰餐厅
- What was it called? - Cha Cha Cha.
对  就是那家
Yeah, that's it.
你可以带我去那里
Well, you can take me there.
星期五晚上十点  可以吗?
Friday night at 10:00. Is that good for you?
绝对没问题  那好
- Yeah, it's perfect. - Good.
怎么没有爆米花  要吃自己去做
- There's no popcorn? - Make your own goddamn popcorn!
好啦  这比代客泊车还方便
All right. Now that's valet parking.
哈瑞  你最近好吗?
- Harry. - What's up, dog?
托你的福  很好  快请进
Excellent, brother. Come on in, man.
这些货你看喜不喜欢  这位又是谁呀
- Check it. It's yours. - What do we got here?
新雇的帮手吗?  少挖苦我了
- Hired some new help, huh? - Don't even think about it.
海克特  近来好吗?  你怎么样?
- What's up, Hector? - How you feelin'?
很好  你需要些什么?
Pretty good. What do you need?
你帮我照着这张单子找  每样要三个
I need you to hook me up. Three of everything. I made a list.
你先看看
Why don't you look that over.
什么时候要?  明天  今天也行
- When do you need this stuff by? - Tomorrow. Today.
现在更好  好
- Now. - Right.
白小子动作蛮快的  贝多  把钱给我
White boys work fast, don't they? Beto.
很好
That's right.
"本田喜美"  你说每样要三个吗?
You said you need three of all this?
对  每样要三个  有办法吗?
Yeah, three of everything. What do you think about that?
你先看我手里的东西
Check this out.
他连呻吟都像警察
He moans like a cop.
布莱恩  这是关键时刻
Brian, this is one of those times...
要非常注意你所说的话
when you need to be very clear about what you say.
如果懂的话就点头
Nod if you understand me.
快点头!
Nod!
坐起来
Sit up.
你到这里来干什么
Tell me what the hell you're doin' down here.
我之所以来这里…
Oh, shit. What I'm doin'.
是因为我还欠你一部极速跑车
I owe... I owe you a ten-second car.
并且和极速大赛有关
And what this is about, this is about Race Wars.
我在里面发现
I just went in there, and Hector is gonna be runnin'...
海克特有三部本田喜美  而且装上史普恩牌的引擎
three Honda Civics with Spoon engines.
除此之外  他还到哈瑞那里
And on top of that, he just came into Harry's...
订购三个T66涡轮压缩引擎
and he ordered three T-66 turbos...
加上氧化亚氮燃料注入器和莫德克牌电脑控制系统
with NOS, and a MoTeC system exhaust.
照你这么说
So, what are you saying?
你要偷进每个人的车库里
You're gonna go around and check everybody's shit out...
去查他们将要开什么车吗?
one garage after another?
对
Yeah.
因为老大  你是知道的…
Because Dom, you know...
我不能再输了
I can't lose again.
他是警察
He's a cop.
一定是警察
He's a cop!
你是警察吗?
You a cop?
咱们出去逛逛
Let's go for a little ride.
走呀!
Walk!
杰西  你守在这里
All right, kid, stand watch.
喂  老大
Hi,Dom
全都没有引擎
There's no engines.
那他们拿什么来比赛?  希望和梦想吗?
What are they plannin' on racin' with? Hopes and dreams?
不知道  我只知道他们狡猾得很
I don't know, but I know they're sneaky as shit...
而且钱也不是问题
and they've got enough money to buy anything.
什么事?
What?
唐  他们来啦
Dom, we got a wolf pack.
强尼和他那伙人  朝你那里去了  速度很快
It's Johnny Tran, and he's comin' your way really fast!
有人来了  快躲
All right, we got company.
布莱恩!
Spilner!
走  快走!
Come on. Move!
泰德  让我问你一个问题
Let me ask you a question, Ted.
你有没有看出那里不对劲
Do you see anything wrong here?
没有
NO.
这里有没有引擎?  没有
- We got no engines, do we? - No!
有没有?  没有
- Do we? - No!
不是说在极速大赛前一个礼拜  就能拿到日产SR-20的引擎吗
Nissan SR-Twenty motors will pull a premium one week before Race Wars, huh?
有可能
Yeah, probably.
你真会讲话  或许是太会讲话了
You're a smart fence, Ted. Maybe too smart.
蓝斯  你觉得哪种好?
What are you feelin', Lance?
密度四十的机油?
Forty weight?
还是密度五十的机油?
Fifty weight?
四十的应该不错
A forty weight sounds nice.
它们到底在哪里?  你最好说实话
Where are they, Ted? Where are they?
够了!    它们在哪里?
- Enough! - Where are they?
在仓库里
They're in a warehouse.
它们在仓库里
They're in a warehouse, man!
泰德  过来亲我的鞋子
Kiss my shoes?
咱们去拿引擎
Let's go get our engines.
后天我的上司  会从华盛顿到这里来
My superiors are flying in from D.C. Day after tomorrow.
我一定得拿些成果给他看  到现在为止我们手上的资料是
I want somethin' to show. Now, we have a top-echelon fence...
一个嘴塞润滑剂管  油嘴滑舌的人  一些自动武器
with a lube hose in his mouth, automatic weapons...
一群亚裔帮派
a jacket full of priors on every one of these Asian punks...
满满一车库的DVD放映机  还有一堆发疯的行为
a garage full of DVD players and generally psychotic behavior.
何不先向强尼下手  等尘埃落定后再决定下一步
Why not move on Tran now, see where we are when the dust settles?
因为我们只掌握到情况  并没有有力的证据
Because all we have is behavior. Let me get some hard evidence...
我们手上所有的  都不是主要的证据
because what we have now is circumstantial...
我们已经知道动机
What we have is probable cause and truckers arming themselves...
和卡车司机准备自己组织  对抗暴力的自卫队
for some good old vigilante mayhem.
告诉我们海克特这个人
Tell us about Hector.
他是拉丁人  一个小角色
Latinos with spear guns. Give me a break.
他仍在替车子装引擎
Hector's still working on the engines for the cars...
但是轮胎不合
but the tires don't match.
谁有香烟  给我一根
Will someone just give me a cigarette?
快给他一根香烟  别给他香烟
- Get him a cigarette. - Don't get him a cigarette.
你不是戒烟了吗  是戒了
- I thought you quit. - Yeah, I did quit.
给我一根烟行不行  快给他香烟
- Just give me a cigarette. - Get him a cigarette.
别给他
NO!
杜洛托这个人呢?  他不像会做这种疯狂事情的人
- Tell me about Toretto. - He's too controlled for this.
他应该不会做这种  自杀式的卡车抢劫行为
I mean, what? Going suicidal on semi trucks? No way.
文斯也许会做  但他不够聪明去策划它
I mean, maybe his buddy Vince, but he's too stupid to pull it off.
我想那家伙的妹妹  蒙住了你的眼睛
I think the kid sister's blurring your vision.
你是什么意思?  我不怪你
- What do you say? - I don't blame you.
监视她也是我的一大享受
I'd get off on her surveillance photos too, buddy.
别打了  你也喜欢动粗了吗?
Knock it off. What? Are you going native on me, Brian?
你最近看过杜洛托的档案吗
Have you read Toretto's file lately?
我已经全都记住了  再看一遍吧
- Yeah. I memorized that file. - Yeah, well, read it again.
你最好看看这些资料
No. Better still. Take a look at these.
记得我曾经告诉过你  他几乎打死一个人吗?
Remember I told you about the guy he nearly beat to death?
他是用三分之四英寸的扭力板手  打伤那个人的
Toretto did this with a 3/4-inch torque wrench.
这就是他的典型自我控制力
He's a model of self-control.
再给我几天时间
I need a few more days.
我还需要几天时间
它将会从下向上卷
What it's gonna do is it's gonna spool up.
我把最大操纵压力设在24
I got this set up for 24 psi.
听说你今晚有个大计划?
You got big plans tonight?
对  我邀蜜雅去吃晚餐
Yeah. We're going out to dinner.
你若伤她的心  我就扭断你的脖子
You break her heart, I'll break your neck.
那种事绝对不会发生
That's not gonna happen.
我给你看样东西
I wanna show you something.
哇!
Wow.
是我和我爸爸改装的
Me and my dad built her.
九百马力的大马力跑车  它是个野兽
900 horses of Detroit muscle. It's a beast.
你知道她在棕榈谷跑多快吗?  多快?
- Know what she ran in Palmdale? - No. What did she run?
九秒跑四分之一哩
Nine seconds flat.
天呀  是我爸爸在开
- God. - My dad was driving.
扭力是那么的强  车身的底盘差点就脱离了
So much torque the chassis twisted coming off the line.
而且非常难控制她
Barely kept her on the track.
那你能开多快?  我从来没开过
- So what's your best time? - I've never driven her.
为什么?
Why not?
因为她让我害怕
Scares the shit out of me.
那是我爸爸  当时他参加职业改装车大赛
That's my dad. He was coming up in the pro stock car circuit.
是那一季的最后一场比赛
Last race of the season.
一个叫肯尼的家伙  在最后转弯时从内线冲出来
A guy named Kenny Linder came up from inside in the final turn...
碰到他的保险杠  让他在时速120时失控撞墙
and clipped his bumper and put him into the wall at 120.
我亲眼看着我爸爸被烧死
I watched my dad burn to death.
我还记得他的呼喊声
I remembered hearing him scream.
那里的人说  在油箱着火前他已经死了
The people that were there said he had died before the tanks blew.
而喊叫声是出自于我
They said it was me who was screaming.
事后大约一个星期我看到肯尼
I saw Linder about a week later.
手上刚好有个扳手  就用它去揍他
I had a wrench, and I hit him.
我并无意拼命的打他
And I didn't intend to keep hitting him...
但当我停下来时  手臂连举都举不起来
but by the time I was done, I couldn't lift my arms.
他在中学里做工友
He's a janitor at a high school.
每天搭巴士上下班
Has to take the bus to work every day.
从此以后  他们不准我参加任何赛车比赛
And they banned me from the tracks for life.
如今我是今朝有酒今朝醉
I live my life a quarter-mile at a time.
其他都无关紧要
Nothing else matters... not the mortgage, not the store...
什么贷款、店的生意  和我的那帮人  全都不重要
not my team and all that bullshit.
只有赛车时的短短十秒钟
For those ten seconds or less...
刹那间我彻底的解脱了
I'm free.
这个帮派是怎么组成的?
So how is it, anyways, that the gang came to be?
什么?  这个帮派
- What? - The gang.
他们不把它叫做帮派
The gang? No, they don't call themselves a gang.
那该怎么称呼呢?  他们称之为团队
- What do they call themselves? - They're a team.
他们叫自己为团队  这个团队是怎么组成的呢?
- They call themselves a team. - How is it the team came to be?
说来话长
Well, that's a whole lot of history.
我有的是时间
I've got time.
文斯和我哥哥一起长大
Vince grew up with my brother.
可惜他一直不成熟
He didn't ever actually grow up, as you can tell.
他们从小就是朋友  至于莱蒂是我们的邻居
But they were friends as kids. And Letty, she lived down the street.
早在她十岁时就对车子着迷了
Always into cars, though, ever since she was ten years old.
所以我哥哥自然引起她的注意
So, naturally, my brother always had her attention.
当她十六岁时…  她却引起你哥哥的注意
- And then she turned 16... - And then she had Dom's attention.
对  这种事是不是很好玩
Yeah. Yeah, it's funny how that works, isn't it?
的确
Yeah.
杰西又是怎么加进来的呢?
How is it thatJesse fits into the whole thing?
杰西和李昂这两个家伙
Well, Jesse and Leon just sort of showed up one night...
有天突然出现后就不走了
and never ever left.
其实这和我哥哥有关  他像是…
It's just the way my brother is. Dom's like...
他像是一块磁铁
He's like gravity.
把大家都吸引进来
Everything just gets pulled to him.
你也一样
Even you.
不是
NO!
吸引我的是你
The only thing that pulled me in was you.
和你哥哥做朋友是额外的奖金
Being friends with your brother is just a bonus.
很好
That's good.
偶尔能排在第一位  感觉上倒是很棒
That's good. That's nice to come first every once in a while.
我们去兜风好吗?
You wanna go for a drive?
喂?  又发生抢案了
- Yeah? - The hijackers have hit again.
比金已经决定在下午五点
Bilkins made his decision. We're gonna move on Johnny Tran...
向强尼和他的手下动手  除非你有异议
and his guys at 1700 hours, unless you say otherwise.
如果同意就说"是"
If you agree, just say yes.
是  那是谁呀?
- Yeah. - Who is that?
打错号码的
Just a wrong number.
是的  长官  我知道  可是…
Yes, sir. Yeah, I know, but...
是…长官
Yeah, yeah. Yes. Yes, sir.
是的  我知道了
Yeah. I got it.
DVD放映机都是合法购买的
The DVD players were purchased legally.
我们只能告强尼和他的党羽  非法持有武器
All we've got on Tran and company are a couple of weapons charges...
和几张超速罚单而已
and some outstanding speeding tickets.
所以他们都出狱罗  是他爸爸来保释他们的
- So they're out. - Yeah. Father bailed 'em out.
奥康纳  你的智商只有这么一点吗?
Is this the kind of intelligence I can expect from you, O'Conner?
你想怨到我头上  我想怨谁就怨谁
- You're gonna put this on me? - I can put it on whoever I want to.
这是我的权力  你根本怨不到我
- Perks of the job. - No way you're gonna put this on me.
安静点  你最好听清楚
Wait a minute. Let me tell you.
不管你用什么方法
I don't care if you have to put a gun to someone's head...
就算暴露身份我也不在乎
and blow your cover to smithereens.
限你在36小时内把案子了结
You got 36 hours to crack this bastard...
否则请你另就高明
or you might wanna be thinkin' about another career.
是杜洛托  绝对是杜洛托
It's Toretto, Brian. It always has been Toretto.
强尼和海克特只是烟雾而已
Tran and Hector are... They're just fumes.
我知道你一直在骗我  问题是
Well, I know you've been lying to me. My question is this:
你有没有因为  蜜雅的关系也在骗自己
Have you been lying to yourself because you can't see past Mia?
他绝不愿意再回牢里去
He won't go back to prison.
坐不坐牢要他自己去决定
Well, that's a choice he's going to have to make.
世上有各式各样的人
There's all kinds of family, Brian.
而你必须做个选择
That's a choice you're gonna have to make.
紧张大师  准备好了吗?
You ready for this, jumpy?
好了
Yeah.
好车  市价是多少?
Nice car. What's the retail on one of those?
老兄  你可负担不起  这可是法拉利
More than you can afford, pal. Ferrari.
赢过他
Smoke 'im.
有什么事不对劲吗?  没什么  我很好
- So what's wrong, Brian? - Nothin', man. I'm fine.
少装蒜了  显而易见的你有心事
Come on. Obviously something's off.
我也和别人一样  心情有好有坏
Look. I have my good days, and I have my bad days, like anybody else.
别失去你那股酷劲  那才是你的饭票
Brian, don't lose that cool. That's your meal ticket.
我的饭票  我连自己的车都负担不起
My meal ticket? What? I can't pay for my own shrimp?
我已经替你改装了一部车  你看这就是我的毛病
- I got your shrimp. - That's one thing about me.
我不接受别人的施舍
You don't understand. I don't need handouts. I don't take handouts.
我要自己去赚
I earn my way, every step.
我必须另外赚些外快  就像你一样
I just gotta make a little something extra on the side, like you.
像我一样  这是什么意思?
What do you mean, like me?
你言下之意是什么?  那就是我的意思
- What's that supposed to mean? - That's what I mean.
像我一样  你在说什么  别想…
- What does that mean, like me? - Don't try...
我不是傻瓜
I'm not stupid, all right?
你改装车子所花的那些钱…
I know there's no way you paid for all that shit under the hood...
老实说你改装车子所花的钱
There's no way you paid for all that shit under the hood of those cars...
光靠替人调整引擎  和卖杂货绝对不够
by doing tune-ups and selling groceries.
不管你的副业是什么  我要参加一份
Now, whatever it is you're in on, I want in on it too.
这是什么?  你自己看
- What is this? - Read it.
这是干什么?  那是地图
- What is this for? - It's directions.
到极速大赛场的地图  先看你的表现
To Race Wars. We'll see how you do.
别的以后再谈
Then we'll talk.
"不准进入——基地关闭  美国政府资产"
兄弟  你好吗?  你好
- How's it goin', bro? - What's up, man?
欢迎参加极速大赛
Welcome to Race Wars.
很好  谢谢你
Great. Thanks a lot.
嘿  宝贝
Baby. Hey, baby.
美女  你应该到观众席上去  否则会被排气喷得满身都是
You should watch from the side. I wouldn't want to get exhaust on you.
少贫嘴  有钱再说话  那咱们就赌你的美臀如何?
- Put your money where your mouth is? - How 'bout I race you for that ass?
想找女人好莱坞大道上多得是
You want ass, why don't you hit Hollywood Boulevard?
若想来一小段刺激赛  赌注是两千
You want an adrenaline rush, it'll be two large.
就在此时此地  你敢吗?
Right here, right now. What's it gonna be?
好  就这么决定
You got it.
又一个送财美人
Another one bites the dust.
让我看看你有什么本事
Come on. What do you got? What ya got?
等会儿见
See ya.
布莱恩  怎么样?  布莱恩,怎么样?
Whoa. Bri, what's up? Whoa. Bri, what's up?
杰西  你怎么了?  你手里拿着什么?
What's up, Jesse? What do you have in your hand?
学你呀  这是车主证
Throwing down the pink slip, just like you.
车主证?是那辆捷达车吗?  对
- The pink slip to what? TheJetta? - Yeah.
你不能拿你爸爸的车来赌  没关系
- You can't bet your dad's car. - It's all right.
我一定会赢  那家伙开的是本田2000
I ain't losin'. This fool is runnin' a Honda 2000. I'll win.
我赢的话  等我爸出狱后手上就会有点钱
That way, me and my dad can roll together when he gets out of prison.
等他杀了你后  又得回牢里去
They're gonna throw him right back in prison after he kills you.
放心  我一定会赢
Shit. I'm up.
想像你得到胜利  杰西  一定要想像你得到胜利
Visualize the win. Visualize the win, Jesse.
这很重要  你一定要听我的话  你的对手是谁?
- I'm serious. Listen to me, man. - Who you racin'?
别和他赌  我保证他绝对  投资了好几十万在那部车上
Don't do it. I bet you he's got more than a hundred grand under the hood.
小子你太早了
Too soon, junior.
该死!
Shit!
喔  天呀!
Oh, God.
快来  我们有麻烦了
Heads up, bro. We got problems.
什么事?  是杰西
- What? - Jesse.
他要去哪里?  他刚拿车主证和强尼赛车
- Where's Jesse goin'? - He just raced Tran for slips.
真要命
Oh, shit.
他到哪里去了?  他去洗车
- Where's he going? - He went to the car wash.
去把我的车子拿来
Whatever. Go fetch my car.
你的车?  现在可不是在你的地盘上
Go fetch your car? We're not on your block anymore.
看清楚你在和谁说话
You'd better watch who you talk to like that.
霹雳小组突击我家  使我家族受辱
SWAT came into my house, disrespected my whole family...
那是因为有人出卖我
because somebody narced me out.
出卖我的人就是你!
And you know what? It was you!
放开他!
Go! Let him go!
把他拉走  别打了!
Get off of him! Get off of him!
唐  冷静点  咱们走
Dom, chill out, man. Come on. Let's go.
我从没出卖过任何人
I never narced on nobody! I never narced on nobody!
蜜雅!
Mia!
求求你不要去  我这么做是为了我们俩
- I'm asking you not to go. - I'm doing this for both of us.
胡说  是为了你自己
Don't give me that crap. You're doing this for you.
为什么你不让我去呢?  你为什么一定要去呢?
- Why are you asking me to stay? - Why do you insist on doing this?
唐  求求你别去
Dom, please, don't.
蜜雅  怎么回事?  什么怎么回事?
- What's goin' on? - What?
你知道我在说什么  不  我不知道
- You know what I'm talkin' about. - No, I don't, Brian.
难道每次唐开车走时  你都会眼眶红红的吗?
So what? You always have tears in your eyes when Dom drives away?
你是怎么搞的嘛?  别装了
- What is the matter with you? - Come on.
半夜三更你哥哥会去哪里呢?
What's your brother racin' off in the middle of the night for?
是不是和卡车有关  你说是不是?
I'm talkin' about the trucks. You know about the trucks?
什么卡车  你在说什么?
No, Brian. What trucks?
烦死人了
Jesus Christ.
又怎么了?  你听我说
- What? - Listen to me.
蜜雅  我是个警察
Mia, I'm a cop.
你在胡言乱语什么
What are you talking about, Brian? What is this?
当我们第一次见面时  我就是卧底警探
Ever since the first time I met you, I've been undercover.
我真的是警探
I'm a cop.
你这个混蛋
You bastard.
去你的
放开我!
Get off of me, Brian!
你听我说
Listen to me!
我可以对天发誓  我对你的感情是真实的
Everything I ever said I felt about you was real, I swear to God.
你一定要相信我  但现在的问题是你哥哥
You have to believe me. But right now, this isn't about you and me.
你哥哥正要去做案  而我们的时间不多了
Your brother's about to pull a job, and we're almost out of time.
那些卡车司机  不会再束手就擒
Those truckers, they're not laying down anymore.
也许今晚他们能得手
They may make it through the night
但是加州所有的执法人员  都会盯上他们
but every law enforcement agency in California is comin' down on 'em.
如果你希望你哥哥、莱蒂
If you don't want anything to happen to your brother, to Letty...
李昂、文斯都能安全无恙  最好现在就和我一起走
to Leon, to Vince, you have to just get in that car with me right now.
你一定要帮我
You have to help me.
你是唯一能帮我的人
Mia, you are the only person that can help me right now.
求求你帮助我
Please, Mia. Please help me.
本田车藏在  某处加热锅炉厂的外面
Civics are stashed somewhere outside of Thermal.
他们是不开回头路的  而十号公路上又有警察在巡逻
They wouldn't double back. And Highway 10's too well-patrolled...
那我们得到什么结论
so what does that leave us with then?
这就是我们的结论
That leaves us with all this.
手机服务  我是奥康纳警探
- Nextel. - Yes, this is Officer O'Conner...
编号是34762
serial number 34762.
我需要追踪一个手机号码
I need a cell phone trace.
手机号码是什么?  蜜雅  手机号码呢?
- What's the cell number? - Mia, what's the cell phone number?
她现在需要唐的手机号码
Come on, Mia. She needs Dom's cell phone number now.
323-555-6439
323-555-6439.
谢谢你  你听到了吗?
Thank you. You get that?
我们少了一个人  所以莱蒂你要开车
All right. We're one man short. Letty, I need you on the left side.
你妹妹说的没错  似乎是有点不对劲
Your sister's right about this one. This don't feel good.
别这么说
Don't do that.
真的好像有问题  别说了
- Something's wrong. - Stop.
我们应该等杰西的
We shouldn't be doing this without Jesse.
这是个大金矿  我们已经盯了三个月
Look. This is the mother lode. We've been on this for three months.
做完这次  大家都可以放长假
After this, it's a long vacation for everyone.
走吧  希望如此
- Let's go. - I hope so.
有一天晚上我做了个梦
Listen. The other night I had a dream that you and I...
梦见我们俩在墨西哥的海滩上
were on a beach in Mexico.
真的吗?  真的
- Really? - Really.
走  先把这件事搞定
Come on. Let's make this happen.
注意扫瞄器  知道了
- Keep on those scanners. - Copy that.
好  我们出发吧
All right. Let's go.
喂
Yeah?
那个手机号码在86号公路北向
We traced the number to the northbound 86...
在科切拉之外  哩程标114的地方
mile 114 outside Coachella.
我们会继续追踪  我来看一下地图
- We'll keep the trace open. - Let me see this.
我们离他们大约40哩
All right. I think we're about 40 miles away.
你打算怎么做呢?
What are you gonna do?
你到底想怎么做
好  开始行动
Okay! Go time!
情况不错  扫瞄器上什么也没有
We're all good, man. I got nothin' on the scanners.
继续注意
Keep goin'.
文斯  快回来!
Don't! Get back in!
司机居然有猎枪  退后  把他弄下来
- He's got a damn shotgun! - Back off! Get him off of there!
该死
Shit.
把我弄下来  靠近点
Get me off this thing! Pull up!
你先把钩子松开  回来
- Unook yourself! - Come back!
快松开  靠近点!
- Do it! - Pull up!
我不能…  你能的
- I can't... - You can do it!
你一靠近我就跳
Pull up! I'll jump!
快点!
Come on!
我去分散他的注意力
I'm pullin' up to distract him.
你们加油呀
Come on, boy.
开枪哪有赛车刺激
Shot doesn't get better than this.
混蛋  你居然真开枪
Son of a bitch!
帮我离开这里  我先把金属线松开
Take me off of here. I'm gonna unook the wire.
再试一次  一、二、三
Try it again. One, two, three!
先把线松开
Unook yourself!
我的手臂被缠住了  你抓住我的手
- I can't get my arm free! - Vince, grab my hand!
我的手臂!    听着  把你的手给我
- My arm! - Listen! Give me your hand!
我的手被缠住了  我会拉你过来
- I can't get my hand free! - I'm gonna pull you off!
唐老大  千万别放弃我
Dominic, hold on! Listen to me!
要命!
Shit!
坚持下去
Hold on!
你走开  我去帮他
Move out of the way! I'm comin' to get him!
莱蒂!    李昂  你回去帮莱蒂
- Yo? - Pull back for Letty.
把她带走  我马上去
- Get her out of there! - I'm on it! Go!
我去帮她  你把文斯救下来
I got her! You get Vince off that truck!
莱蒂
Come on, baby.
你没事吧
You okay?
你还好吗?让我看看
Come on, girl. You all right? Come on. Let me look at you.
快  我们得走了
Come on. We gotta go. Let's go.
你来开车  你是什么意思?
- Take the wheel! - What do you mean?
把脚踩在油门上
Put your foot on the gas!
你想干什么?  我去救他
- What the hell are you gonna do? - I'm gonna get him.
快踩油门  好!
- Put your foot on the gas! - Okay!
稳住车子  可以了
- All right. Keep it steady. - I got it!
文斯  坚持下去
All right. Hold on, Vince!
他的情况不好  再靠近点
He's having a hard time holding on! Get me a little closer!
好
All right!
再靠进一点  我正在接近
- Closer! - I'm moving in!
好  保持这个距离
Hold it right there!
跳!    你要和我合作
- Go! - You gotta hang in with me!
我们会把你弄下去  把你的手臂给我
We're gonna get you off this thing! Give me your arm!
看着我  千万别放手
Look at me. Don't let go.
文斯  用手臂抱着我
Come on, Vince! Throw this arm around me!
别放手
Don't let go.
文斯!  靠近点
Come on, Vince! Get closer!
再靠近点
Vince, get closer! Come on!
好了  你先下去
Here we go.
我要跳了
Gotta jump.
糟糕
Shit.
宝贝  不会有问题的  我爱你
It's gonna be okay, baby. I love you.
你去照顾她
Watch her.
文斯  撑下去
Come on, Vince. Hang in there!
救护车得在十分钟内到达  否则他就死定了
If we don't get him to an ambulance in ten minutes, he's dead.
你按着这里  我会的
- Hold this. Hold the pressure. - I got it.
别放手  把他的手臂抬高
Don't let go. Hold his arm up.
我是奥康纳警探
Yeah. Yeah, this is Officer Brian O'Conner.
现在不在职勤中
I'm off-duty M.A.P.D.
我立刻需要一架救护直升机
I need a life flight rollout right away.
我的位置是在86号公路  哩程标147
My twenty is Highway 86, mile marker 147.
这里有一位重伤遇难者  大约24岁、六尺高、200磅
I got one trauma victim, about 24 years of age, six foot  maybe 200 pounds.
右臂的割口很深、动脉出血
He's got a deep laceration to his right arm with arterial bleeding.
他的左脚被猎枪近距离射伤
And he's got a shotgun wound, close-range, to his left leg.
是的
Yeah.
他刚进入休克状态
Yeah. And he's going into shock.
唐  把枪放下来
Put the gun down now!
把你的车开走  放屁  把枪放下来
- Move your car. - Bullshit. Put it down now!
不要再逃了  我没有逃
- No more running. - I'm not running!
李昂和莱蒂呢?  他们早就走了
- Where's Leon and Letty? - They're long gone.
一切都结束了  我没叫警察  但别逼我
Then it's over. I didn't call the police, but don't push me.
把枪放下来  我发誓…  你就是警察
- Put the gun down! I swear to Go... - You are the cop!
你就是警察呀!
You're a cop!
我必须在他们之前找到杰西
Brian, I gotta find Jesse before they do.
这孩子只能靠我  我可以叫警方寻找他的车牌
- I'm all the kid's got. - I'll call in the plates.
一定会在强尼之前找到他的
P.D.'ll pick 'im up way before Johnny even gets near 'im.
把你的车开走  拜托你们别吵了
- Move your car. - Dom, stop it! It's over! Please!
蜜雅  没你的事  把你的…
Mia, stay out of it. Move the...
唐  对不起  我不知道自己在做什么
I am so sorry. I don't know what I'm doin'.
我吓得要死  不知道该怎么办
I'm so scared right now. I don't know what's goin' on.
杰西  你的脑袋在想些什么?  我吓呆了
- What were you thinkin', man? - I don't know. I panicked.
我真不知道自己在干什么  求求你帮帮我
I'm sorry. I don't know what I'm doing. Will you please help me?
杰西!
Jesse
叫救护车  你去叫救护车
Call 911. You, call 911!
当我念高中时常来这里
I used to drag here back in high school.
从这里到平交道是四分之一哩
That railroad crossing up there is exactly a quarter-mile away.
绿灯一亮我就会冲过去
On green, I'm goin' for it.
我没料到会是这样的结果
That's not what I had in mind.
你知道自己在做什么吗?
- You know what you're doin'?
我还欠你一部极速跑车
- I owe you a ten-second car.
我是今朝有酒今朝醉
I live my life a quarter-mile at a time.
其他都无关紧要
Nothing else matters.
只有赛车时的短短十秒钟
For those ten seconds or less...
刹那间我彻底的解脱了
I'm free.